Guide to the John I. Brauman Papers SC1408
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John I. Brauman Papers
1987-1996
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Brauman, J. I. (John I.)
SC1408
4.75 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Faculty recommendations are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2018.
Scope and Contents
Papers include research files, teaching materials, and faculty recommendation files.
Biographical / Historical
John I. Brauman earned an SB from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1959, and a PhD from the University of California at Berkeley in 1963. Following a National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship at the University of California, Los Angeles, he accepted a position at Stanford University where he is now J. G. Jackson - C. J. Wood Professor of Chemistry Emeritus, and serves as Associate Dean of Research. Biographical information from: https://chemistry.stanford.edu/people/john-brauman.
Chemistry, Organic.; Chemistry -- Study and teaching.; Brauman, J. I. (John I.); Stanford University. Department of Chemistry.
- Research
  - Science Editorials (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Org Symp Slides (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - SRI - Coal Compustion - Copies (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ICR Slides and Prints (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photo Detachment (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proton Transfer Talk (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Displacement Reactions (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - O2 Binding Talk (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Euchem (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Displacements (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - I.R. Multiple Photon / Ion Molecule Dynamics (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - FT - ICR (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dimethyllsilyl Anion (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photodetachment Data (Originals), S. Berger, 1990 Oct (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Disscrtation Defense Berger, 1991 Oct (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Me2SiH- (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thesis Pictures (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Talk Pictures (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Proton Transfer Poster (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notes + Talks from Meetings (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ostenheld (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ostenheld (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Isotope Effect Slides (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - CRAIG - John's Germany Talk (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - CRAIG - Dynamics of Intermediates Slides and Disk with lots more, too (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Craig Ke Controller - Kinectic Energy Controller Slides (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Regan (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Overheads, 1995 June (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Romer Dipole (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Craig (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Thesis Talk (BDW) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Thesis Defense Slides Wilbur (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sn2 Dynamics Slides Wilbur (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Brian Wladkowski (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - To Do, Slides, 1990 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Slides (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Wilbur (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Biogenex (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - IBM Ramus (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Picogram, Inc (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Research Corporation (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Alkylflourene Proton Exchange (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Distributions_Talk_Overheads (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Diene Isomerization (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Hydrocarbon Isomerization (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Base catalyzed rearrangements (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Asubiojo Original Figures (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - McPeters Drawings (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Slides JIB, Saloman (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dodd Drawings (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Moylan (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Repromasters RNR (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Thesis Drawings RNR (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Slides Mich State (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Slides (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Slides (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Complexes (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Photo Cleavage (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carboxylic Acids (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dynamics Talks (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SF6 - Talk (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - (Untitled) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Phenyl Nitreue (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photodetachment Talk (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - (Untitled) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mass Spec Mtg. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - IR Photo Talk, Ion-Molecule Dynamics (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Teaching
  - Chemistry 233 Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chemsitry 233 Forms (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chemistry 229 - Memos (Current) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chemistry 223 - Old Memos (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry 223 - Committee Assign. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry 223 Memos, 1987 - 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry 229 - Old Seminar Memos (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry 229 - Old records (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Faculty Recommendations
  Conditions Governing Access
  Faculty recommendation files are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
  - Andersen, Hans C (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bergman, Robert G. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boxer, Steven G. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Collman, James P. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Djerassi - Maison de la Chemie (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Djerassi, Carl - Tyler Prize Nom, 1994 Mar (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Djerassi, Carl - Tyler Prize Nom. Deadline:, 1996 Sep 16 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Djerassi, Carl - Nominations (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Du Bois, Justin (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fayer, Michael D. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Finke, Richard G. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hampton, Philip D (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Khosla, Chaitan (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Kodadek, Thoomas J. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Kool, Eric T. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Moylan, Christopher R. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Nelson, Norvell J. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Raybuck, Scott A. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ross, John - National Medal of Science nomination - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sessler, Jonathan L. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sharpless, K.B. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Skoog, Douglas A. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Solomon, Edward I. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Stack, Dan (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Ross, John (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Zare, R. N. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Taube, Henry (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Trost, B.M. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Wandless, Thomas J (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Waymouth, Robert M (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Weinstein, Rebecca (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Wender, Paul (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Zaffavoui, Alejandro (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Ross, John (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - McConnell, Harden M (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Moerner, W. E. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Khosla, Chaitan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hodgson, Keith (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Herschlag, Daniel (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Suslick, Kenneth S. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tumas, William (Box 5, Folder 8)